

@

dpk1391981@gmail.com

0

+91-8285257636

0

Delhi, DL 110092

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Applications: Pursuing MCA **Jain University**, Bangalore, January 2023

Bachelor of Commerce **Delhi University**, Delhi, 2017 Delhi University,— B.com, degree

High School Diploma **Ambedkar Institute Of Technology**, Delhi, 2016 Diploma in CS/IT for 3 yr.

# **LINKDIN**

 https://www.linkedin.com/in /deepak-kumar-3bb60112a/

# DEEPAK KUMAR

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software development with over 6+ years of successful experience in IT industry . Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in IT industry with having hands on Backend and Frontend technology in web like Node/PHP/React/Javascript etc.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming Language:
  Javascript, Typescript, Node, PHP
- Web Services: API (Rest full),
- Backend FrameWork: Express Js, Nest Js, CakePHP
- DevOps: AWS services (Dynamodb, Lambda, AWS cognito, EC2, SES, S3, AWS Amplify, API Gateway)
- **UI Framework**: Next JS, React js, jquery, Bootstrap, Material UI
- Testing Tools: Jest

- State Management: Redux tool
- Database: MySql, NoSQL(DynamoDB And MongoDB)
- OS: Linux ubuntu
- Version Control: GIT
- **Development Tools:** Github, GitLab, Bitbucket, JIRA

#### **WORK HISTORY**

September 2017 - Current

Instant system inc - Software Engineer, Noida, NCR

- (6+ yr) Currently working in this organization from last 6+ year as a position of Software Engineer, involved as a backend engineer.
- Currently using technology from 6+ year Nest JS, Next Js, Node js, React js, MySql, NoSQL, AWS Services.

December 2016 - August 2017

Phoenix Media Pvt Ltd - Software Developer, New Delhi, Delhi

 Worked here around 8 month - with technology PHP (Codeigniter) and on Front end Javascript/Jquery

# **PROJECTS**

## Humanize (Social Platform)-

https://humanize.com/

Description: Its offer a healthy digital global platform supporting personal development through an innovative science-based curriculum and inter-subjective dyadic practices with high level teachers, regular coaching, and a community to support ongoing and sustainable practice and inner transformation. Roles and Responsibilities: Sr software engineer (Full stack).

Technology: Node js, React js, Nest js, MonogoDB, Redux.

#### SYNQY (Product Advertisements Portal)—

https://portal.synqy.net/portal/synqy

Description: This is an advertisement portal or a product for an advertising

company (SYNQY) US based.

Roles and Responsibilities: Support backend service as an API. Technology: Node js, React js, Serverless, AWS lambda, mysql,

### Ceekr (Social Platform) -

https://www.ceekr.com/home

Description: This is social platform for who find spiritual content, Create portals for

guru's, leader's etc.

Roles and Responsibilities: Support backend development, managing APIs,

manage UI part as well.

Technology: React Js, Javascript mysql, jQuery,

#### IprofileConnectector —

https://iprofileconnector.herokuapp.com/

Description: This is an simple connecting profile of user and see there skills.

Roles and Responsibilities: Support backend service as an API.

Technology: Nodejs, Express js, React js, MongoDB

## Galaxy Tourism(CRM) —

http://galaxytourism.in

Description: CRM for tour and travel, Roles and Responsibilities: Backend software

developer using PHP technology and mysql.

Technology: PHP(codeigniter), mysql

## Foodsafety(CRM) -

Description: CRM for auditing stores and generate reports Roles and

Responsibilities: Backend software developer using PHP technology and mysql.

Technology: PHP(codeigniter), mysql.

# **AWARD**

## **Rising star**

: For best performance of the year 2018-19 in instant system inc